Guy van der Meulen

Gamesystems & Tools
Programmer



Personal



Guy van der Meulen



Guy_lvdm@hotmail.com



+31 630970166



Netherlands, Breda



linkedin.com/in/guy-van-dermeulen

Skills

Unity	•••••
Unreal Engine	••••
C++	••••
C#	••••
GitHub	••••
Perforce	••••
Jira	••••
Confluence	••••
Visual Studio	••••
.NET	••••
MySQL	••••
Jenkins CI	••••
Java	••••

About me

I am a skilled programmer with experience in AAA game development settings and a deep passion for creating robust game systems and tools that enhance production. I have tuned my expertise through university projects, formal education, and internships.

Platforms: Windows | PS4 | Raspberry PI OS

(Experience in order)

Languages: C++ | C# | C | Java | HTML & CSS | SQL

Portfolio: guyvdm.github.io

Education

Bachelor's degree, Creative Media & Game Technologies

sep 2020 - jul 2024

Breda University of Applied Sciences, Breda

• In these 4 years, I have worked in big interdisciplinary teams. Worked in Triple AAA professional settings, worked on multiple custom engines, released a game from Pre-Production to Release for a year to Steam. Released various games (Itch 4 games, Steam 1). Worked on my own raytracer. Learned crossplatform development for PS4. Learned OpenGL on a crossplatform project for both Windows Raspberry OS and learned shaders. Worked on games in teams of up to 30 people. Made full use of the agile work flow & scrum.

Level 4 VET, Game Architecture & Design

jun 2016 - jul 2020

Deltion College, Zwolle

Learned the basics of all discplines within gamedevelopment, ranges from 3D modelling, to design & programming using C# in Unity & .Net. Worked on numerous game projects, learned network programming and have done two internships for Game & Software Engineer.

Work Experience

Gamesystems & Network Engineer - Attic Panic

sep 2022 - jul 2023

. . .

Lil Spoops, Breda

- Worked on the back-end networking, gameplay synchronization, abilities, server browsing, lobby system & UX.
- Done playtesting, UI implementation, steamworks setup, smoketesting and many code reviews.
- Interdisciplinary team 30 people.
- Game is released on Steam.

Gamesystems & Tools Engineer - SUB Nivis

mei 2022 - jul 2022

TheOtherEngine, Breda

- Project is done completely in C++ using ENTT workflow & Bullet for collision.
- Worked on all gameplay-bound elements, contributed to our level editor tool for designers, scripted animations & UX.
- Worked with Jenkins as our main CI pipeline.

C •••••

Figma

Trello

3D Studio Max

Languages

Dutch
English
Bulgarian

Hobbies and interests

Working on my own Game & tools, Guitar, Runescape, Japanese Culture, Physical Exercise, Retro Games • Interdisciplinary team - 15 people.

Internships

Software Developer Intern

aug 2019 - feb 2020

VR Owl, Utrecht

 Refactoring VR-Online server & game both in .NET & Unity using dependency injection. Worked on VR Online Experience for Coca Cola in Unity using photon as my networking back-end. Worked on an online VR application demo solo for watching videos together in a singular space with Voicechat for a customer.

Software Developer Intern

feb 2019 - jul 2019

MindMansion, Eindhoven

Worked on VR Driving Simulator in Unity aimed towards people with the fear
of driving. Worked on in house tooling aimed to make the screening process
easier for staff & the client their working with.

Personal Projects

2D MMO Engine (C++, Windows)

okt 2023

- Created client/server architecture using ENet, recreating the core mechanics of a well-known MMO 'Runescape' in 2D.
- Created external editor application for creating parts of the overworld.
 Serializes data using Cereal and exports data used both by client & server for purposes such as visualizing the world, sanity checking, anti-cheat, pathing and more.

Neolocus - (Unity, Android)

2020

- Working on a bullethell game for android in Unity.
- Researched and applied best practices for phone UI and UX design, learning how to create dynamic and responsive visuals to improve the user experience on mobile devices.